Unlike you guys...
（ナルト）お前と違って俺は…。
つながってたもんを
切りたかねえし→
I don't want to sever
any of my bonds...
or get them cut off!
切られたくもねえんだよ！
（オビト）切るべきではなかったな。
We shouldn't have cut them.
（マダラ）消えろ。
Disappear!
Hole
Fire Style: Majestic Flower Flame!
火遁　豪火滅却！
Fire Style: Bomb Blast Dance!
火遁　爆風乱舞！
うわっ…。
むっ！
クッ…。
助かった。
We're safe!
If we didn't have
Naruto's Chakra Cloak,
《チョウジ：ナルトのチャクラの
衣がなかったら→
we'd be crisper than a roast pig!
ブタの丸焼き以上になってたよ》
（サクラ）次が来る！
The next round is coming!
はっ！
Naruto's chakra has been protecting
everyone this whole time.
《ナルトのチャクラがみんなを
ずっと守ってくれてる。
こんなこと続けてて大丈夫なの
ナルト？》
Naruto, are you sure
you're okay to keep this going?
ハァ　ハァ…。
いねえ！
（キバ）どこに行った？
He's gone!
Where'd he go?
♪♪（キラービー）
「やつが消えた　やつは逃げた」
He disappeared... He escaped...
（八尾）んなわけねえだろ　捜せ！
That's impossible. Find him!
（カカシ）上だ　ナルト！
Above you, Naruto!
ナルト　みんなをかばい
防戦ばかりになってきてるぞ。
Naruto, you're only fighting
defensively now,
trying to protect everyone.
ハァ　ハァ…。
この状況に意味があるのか？
Is there any meaning to all of this?
（九喇嘛）大丈夫か？　ナルト。
Are you all right, Naruto?
It's too much for you to control
the chakra that I gave you, all at once.
渡したチャクラを一度に
コントロールするのは無茶すぎる。
すぐにバテるぞ。　それに十尾が
チャクラをためてやがるようだ。
You'll wear yourself out
in no time.
Also, it looks like Ten Tails
is charging chakra,
気ぃつけろ。
ハァ　ハァ…。
so you'd better watch out!
ただ弱っていくだけだな。
You're only growing weaker.
一人になりてぇ　てめえに
わかんねえだろうけどよ→
I don't think you'd understand,
since you want to be alone...
俺の近くにみんながいてくれる。
But having everyone by my side
makes me really, really happy!
俺はそれが
すっげえ嬉しいんだよ！
That alone gives me strength!
そんだけで力が湧いてくる！
クッ！
逃げたか？
Did he run away?
If the pain of your comrades' deaths
is part of your bond...
仲間の死の痛みを
つながりとのたまうなら→
仲間を無理に守る
必要もなかろう？
then there's no need
to protect them, right?
なんだよ　ヘリクツ野郎。
お前のそういうところが→
What the hell,
you quibbling bastard?!
That's what I hate about you!
メチャメチャ大嫌いだ！
That's not what I‘m talking
about you, quibbling idiot!
そういうこと言ってんじゃ
ねえんだよ　ヘリクツバカが！
I'm saying I can endure any pain
if it involves my comrades.
仲間のことなら　どんだけ痛くても
我慢するっつってんだ！
それを捨てたくねえって
言ってんだ！
It means I don't want
to give them up!
わがままかもしんねえけど…。
It might seem selfish
of me...
ここに仲間がいねえのが
いちばんイテエんだよ　俺は！
But it's more painful for me to not
have any comrades in here!
以上！
《オビト　お前はナルトで
何を確かめてる？》
Obito... What are you trying to
confirm through Naruto?
ヘッ。
《しゃ～んなろ！》
Cha!
《やはり間違いない。
このチャクラ…。
There's no mistake!
This chakra is...
柱間！》
Hashirama!
親父　崩れるぞ！
ウッ　抑えきれん…！
Dad! It's collapsing!
I can't hold it back any longer!
クソッ　このナルトチャクラありきの
山土の術を…。
Damn it, it's repelling
this Mountain Jutsu
enhanced with Naruto's chakra!
これ以上　足止めする術は
もうねえぞ　親父！
There's no other jutsu
that can stop it, Dad!
ナルト　やべえぞ！
Bad news, Naruto!
十尾は天変地異をやるつもりだ。
The Ten Tails is planning to
do the Cataclysm!
えっ　何だよ　それ…　てっぺん？
What the heck is that?
Cat-a-what?
のんきにかまえてんじゃねえ！
天地が裂けるぞ。
Stop wasting time!
The land's going to
be ripped apart!
唯一　つながってた
俺と十尾を切るからだ。
It can't be controlled anymore,
because you cut the link
between Ten Tails and me.
抑えがきかんぞ。
Although I guess it's about time
I became its Jinchuriki.
もうそろそろ人柱力に
なったほうがいいんだろうがな。
これからだぞ　楽しいのは。
The real fun...
is just beginning!
《十尾を今度こそ消す》
This time, I'll make
the Ten Tails disappear!
神威！
Kamui!
狙ってたようだが
それは俺も同じだ　カカシ。
Looks like you were waiting
for your chance.
But so was I, Kakashi.
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
Naruto, you take care
of things here!
ナルト　こっちを頼む。
Kakashi Sensei!
カカシ先生。
（九喇嘛）くるぞ　天変地異だ！
Here it comes! The Cataclysm!
That should have cleaned
most of them out.
さすがに少しは掃除できたろう。
んっ？
Naruto protected us again.
《また　ナルトが守ってくれたんだ》
《ヒナタ：ナルト君》
Naruto...
効かねえな。
Is that all you've got?
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
クッ…。
消えてく。
It's disappearing!
ハァ　ハァ…。
強がっても　ここまでのようだな。
Nice try pretending to be tough, but
it seems you've reached your limit.
次の楽しみも出来たことだ→
You've given me something
to look forward to...
but I think it's time
you made your exit.
ご退場　願おうか　そろそろ。
Everyone! Let's join together
and fight as one!
皆さん　力を合わせていきますよ。
- Right!
（みんな）お～！
ヒナタ。
Hinata!
あんたは回復。
Time for you to recover!
《みんな…》
You guys...
無駄なことだ。
Such a futile demonstration.
Lightning Blade!
雷切！
フッ　やはり
お前の心には迷いがある。
So there's still doubt
in your heart.
今までにも俺をやろうと思えば
やれたはずだ。
You've had several chances to
kill me if you really wanted to.
((更に　もう一発))
One more blow!
It's pathetic that
you feel compassion
（オビト）あのお前が戦争中に
敵に情けをかけるとはな。
towards an enemy
in the midst of fighting.
後ろめたさか？
Is it guilt?
リンを守れなかったと…。
Are you feeling remorse
over the fact that
俺との約束を
守れなかったことで→
you couldn't protect Rin and
keep your promise to me?
気がとがめたか？
俺を改心でもさせるつもりか？
Are you hoping that
I'll have a change of heart?
オビト　もうやめにしてくれないか。
Obito... Let's stop this already!
お前のかつての夢は
火影になることだった。
Your dream long ago was
to become the Hokage...
ナルトはな　今でもそうなんだよ。
Naruto has the same dream.
Naruto's words are exactly
what you used to say in the past.
ナルトの言葉は
かつてのお前の言葉と同じだ。
I'm going to be the Hokage!
I'm Obito Uchiha!
((俺は　火影になる！
うちはオビトだ。
For my Great Stone Face,
んでもって　俺の火影岩には→
make sure my trademark goggles
and Sharingan are nicely carved out!
トレードマークのゴーグルと→
更に写輪眼も
しっかり彫ってもらう。
将来の夢は　火影をこす！
My dream is to surpass
the Hokage someday!
んでもって　里のやつら全員に→
And...I'm going to make everyone
in the village accept me!
(俺の存在を認めさせてやるんだ))
お前は　知らず知らずのうちに→
You haven't realized it...
かつての自分と今のナルトを重ね→
But you've been trying to merge
your past self with the current Naruto...
ナルトの言葉を
かつての己の言葉として→
Hearing the old you
in Naruto's words.
聞きたがってる。
お前自身　かつての自分に
否定されたいと→
Is it because you secretly want
to be repudiated by your old self?
望んでるんじゃないのか？
ナルトの気持が
わからないお前じゃないはずだ。
I can't see you not understanding
Naruto's feelings!
お前は　まだ戻れる。
You can still go back...
to the person you once were!
昔の自分をもう一度。
クッ　ハハハハッ　ハハハハッ…。
ナルトの心のうちが
わかっているからこそ→
It's because I understand
Naruto's mind...
That I want to hear it all...
そのすべてを聞いて→
そのすべてを
否定してやりたくてね。
And negate everything
that he does!
《オビト》
Obito...
By the way, let me tell you
one more thing.
それと　もう１つ言っておくが→
お前が俺に対して後ろめたく
思うこと自体　おこがましいのさ。
This guilt you feel towards me
is really presumptuous.
俺が戦争をおこした理由が→
If you believe that I started
this war simply over you and Rin...
お前とリンのことだけだと
思っているなら→
見当違いもいいところだ。
To call you misdirected,
would be an understatement!
知っているさ　すべて。
I know everything.
リンが自ら　お前の雷切に突っ込み→
I know that Rin deliberately ran
into your Lightning Blade.
己で死を選んだことも。
That she chose to die.
（オビト）あのとき
リンは　霧隠れにさらわれて→
Back then, Rin had been kidnapped
by the Hidden Mist
三尾の人柱力にされていた。
and forced to become
the Three Tails' Jinchuriki.
お前は　リンを奪還することに成功し
連れ出したが→
You succeeded in rescuing Rin
and got her out...
But that was part of
the Hidden Mist's plan.
それが　そもそも
やつら霧隠れの作戦だった。
（オビト）お前たちを
木ノ葉へ追いたてるために→
They even pretended
to pursue you
追いかけるフリまでしてな。
to get you home
to the Leaf quicker.
お前　それをどうして。
How did you...?
((うっ　クソッ！
Damn it!
みんなは　ここに残れ。
You all stay here.
隊長　増援を待ちましょう。
Captain... Let's wait
for reinforcements.
時間はない。
We don't have time...
The Hidden Mist kidnapped Rin
in order to use her
霧隠れは　リンを　何かの→
実験体に使おうとして
さらったんだ。
as some kind of test subject...
血霧の里まで連れて行かれたら
もう　助けることは　不可能だ。
If she's taken to
the Blood Mist Village,
we'll never get her out.
１人では　無理です！
１人じゃない。
But you can't go alone!
I won't be alone.
（カカシ）口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
（カカシ）リンの匂いは？
（パックン）覚えている　任せろ。
Can you pick up Rin's scent?
I remember it. Leave it to me.
増援が来たら伝えろ→
When the reinforcements arrive,
tell them that we went after Rin.
俺たちは　リンを追って　先行したと。
わかりました。
Yes, sir.
Wait for me, Rin!
《待っていろ　リン。
I will definitely protect you!
お前は　絶対に守る！》
It's the Leaf!
木ノ葉だ！　木ノ葉の忍だ！
A Leaf shinobi!
よし　このまま
敵を引きつけるぞ。
All right! We're going
to divert the enemy!
You guys wait here.
おぬしらは　ここで待て。
こっちだ　カカシ。
This way, Kakashi.
リン！
Rin!
（パックン）幻術で意識を。
（カカシ）解！
They put her under a genjutsu.
Release!
（リン）あっ　カカシ！
Kakashi!
Let's get out of here!
逃げるぞ。
木ノ葉の忍。
捕虜も一緒だぞ。
Leaf shinobi!
They have the captive!
急げ！
Hurry!
逃がすな！
バウッ！　バウッ！
Don't let them get away!
ゆけ　拙者たちも　これより
敵を引きつけにかかる。
Go!
We'll divert the enemy.
頼んだぞ。
なに　拙者たちは→
Thanks, I leave it to you.
Save it.
If we're driven into a corner,
we'll make a run for it too.
追い詰められたら
退散するまでよ。
行くぞ　リン！
Let's go, Rin.
カカシ　私　何か変。
Kakashi...
I...feel strange...
今は　とにかく　逃げるんだ。
散！
We have to escape first.
Scatter!
I feel it...
何かを感じるの
私の中に　もう１人→
I feel like there's someone,
something else inside me.
何かがいるような感じ。
どういうことだ？
What are you talking about?
わからない。
I don't know.
いたぞ！
逃がすな！
- There they are!
- Don't let them get away!
突っ切るぞ！
We have to get past them!
霧の忍は　私に
儀式を施そうとしてたわ。
The Hidden Mist tried to perform
some kind of ritual on me.
何か　特別な儀式。
A special ritual.
だけど　私は　意識を奪われて。
But I lost consciousness and...
あっ！
しつこいやつらだ。
They're persistent!
I can't return to the Leaf Village!
私は　木ノ葉には　戻れない。
何を言っている。
What are you saying?!
Kakashi, you have to kill me now!
カカシ　すぐに　私を殺して！
何を言っているんだ　リン！
What are you saying, Rin?!
私は　利用されてる。
They're using me.
このままだと
木ノ葉を襲うかもしれないの。
If I return, Hidden Leave Village
may be attacked!
オビトに　お前を守ると約束した。
I promised Obito that
I would protect you!
そんなことは　絶対にできない。
I can't do such a thing!
（カカシ）何か別の方法が
きっとある。
There's got to be a way
out of this!
In any case, we need
to make it to the village!
今は　とにかく里まで逃げるんだ。
ダメよ　カカシ。
俺が　やつらを食い止める。
No, Kakashi...
I'll stop them.
(（カカシ）いけ！
ダメよ！))
Now go!
I can't...
（オビト）霧隠れは　リンが木ノ葉に
戻った時点で→
Once Rin made it back
to the Leaf,
the Hidden Mist intended to make
the Three Tails rampage
リンの中の三尾を暴走させ→
and attack the village.
木ノ葉を襲わせるつもりで
いたのだ。
((ああ！))
（オビト）リンは　それがわかっていて→
Rin realized this...
敵に向けたお前の雷切を利用し→
And took advantage of the Lightning Blade
you aimed at the enemy...
自害した。
to commit suicide.
（オビト）愛する人の手によって
死ぬことを決めたのだ。
She made up her mind to die
at the hands of the one she loved.
木ノ葉を守るために。
In order to protect
the Hidden Leaf.
たとえ　お前がどう言おうと→
No matter what you say,
to me, you're still an impostor
who couldn't protect Rin.
俺にとって　リンを守れなかった
お前は　ニセモノだ。
（オビト）リンは　俺の中では
死ぬべき人ではない。
To me, Rin is someone
who wasn't supposed to die.
よって　死んだリンは
ニセモノでしかない。
So Rin dead is also an impostor.
リンは　生きていてこそ　リンなのだ。
Rin is Rin because she is alive!
こんな状況ばかりを作ってきた
忍のシステム　里　そして　その忍たち。
The things that created
all these circumstances...
The system of shinobi, village,
and the shinobi themselves...
（オビト）俺が　本当に絶望したのは
世界そのもの。
What caused me to despair,
is this world itself.
このニセモノの世界にだ！
This counterfeit world!
ナルトが言ったはずだ。
Remember Naruto's words?
心に本物の仲間がいないのが
いちばん痛いんだって。
That it's most painful
not to have real comrades
inside one's heart?
（カカシ）俺は　あの子に
かつてのお前の言葉を→
I quoted exactly what
you said long ago to him...
そのまま伝えた。
かつてのお前なら
ナルトと同じことを感じ　言うはずだ。
I know the old you would have
resonated with that.
そして　今でもそうだと…。
And I still believe
the current you, can as well-!
見てみろ！
Look!
（オビト）俺の心には
何もありゃしない。
There's nothing in my heart!
今はもう　痛みさえ感じやしない。
（オビト）
後ろめたく思わなくていい　カカシ。
この風穴は　この地獄の世界に
開けられたものだ。
かつての俺のここには
痛みしかなかった。
それに何の意味がある？
だから　すべてを捨てた。
お前だって
ずっと苦しんでいるだろう。
（オビト）リンの墓の前で…
俺の墓の前で。
カカシ　もういいんだ。
お前も　もう苦しまなくていい。
（オビト）リンは　ここにいる。
((好きだよ　カカシ))
（オビト）お前にとって
理想の俺も一緒にな。
((俺は　火影になるぞ！))
好きなものを望め。
（オビト）この幻術の世界では
すべて手に入る。
お前の心の穴も
すぐに埋められる。
リンは　もういないんだ。
それにお前は
まだ生きているだろう。
こんなので…　こんなもので→
本気で心の穴が埋まるとでも
思ってるのか！
（カカシ）生きていたリンの思いまで
消すなよ！
リンは　命をかけて里を守り
残そうとしたんだ。
（カカシ）一人で妄想ばかり
穴に詰め込んでみても→
心の穴が埋まるわけがない！
また変化してるぞ。
今夜の幕開けは　出演者全員による
この歌からです。
夏らしく　盆踊りの雰囲気を
お楽しみください。